Nicolas Gongora Salazar

Contact

nicolas@ncodes.dev | (57) 319 706-9294 | LinkedIn | GitHub

Based in Colombia

Senior Javascript Engineer

6+ years of experience as a Software Engineer focused on Javascript technologies. 4+ years as a remote worker for Silicon Valley companies such as **Reddit** and **Rivian**. Development of web, mobile, and backend applications using tools such as Typescript, React, Redux, React Native, Sass/Less, Node.js, express, and AWS. Unit testing and code review. Passionate Teacher.

Experience

Sr. Software Engineer at Reddit, Inc. June 2022 – December 2022 · Remote (San Francisco, CA)

Build new features for the Reddit web app both for desktop and mobile screens. Deployment to production and management of versions and feature flags. Maintenance of Reddit internal libraries and third-party dependencies.

Angular. Typescript. npm. Grafana. Docker.

Sr. Software Engineer at Rivian January 2021 – June 2022 · Remote (Irvine, CA)

Development of web app features for handling Rivian's manufacturing, requesting and shipping processes. UX and performance improvements. Build of AWS lambda microservices and integration using GraphQL.

React. Typescript. Redux. AWS Lambda. AWS Amplify. GraphQL.

Sr. FullStack Engineer at Smarthop March 2019 – January 2021 · Remote (Miami, FL)

Build of web and mobile apps features for extracting and processing data of american truckers loads and profits. Programming of web scrapping and use of performance improvement techniques as virtualization.

React. Redux. nodeJS. MongoDB. Redis. Puppeteer. express.

Lead Software Engeineer at Insercor March 2017 – April 2018 · Hybrid (Cota, Colombia)

Team leadership for transforming an internal use app into flexible modules for external customers. Maintenance of the software product, deployments, mentoring and participation in the recruitment process as technical interviewer.

React. Firebase. Google Cloud Platform. Jira. Confluence.

Education

BE, Mechanical Engineering Universidad Santo Tomás Class of 2019 Bogotá, Colombia

Mathematician Universidad El Bosque Degree expected Bogotá, Colombia

Skills

Technical React Typescript Javascript React Testing Library Node.js Express AWS Lambda

Soft Mentoring Communicative Interviewer Attitude



Teacher Career



Since 2018, I teach about Math and Programming on friday nights and saturdays. It has been an amazing and grateful adventure and one of the most important aspects of my carrer as Software Engineer; I never thought that your students could teach you so much.

Teacher at Politécnico Colombo Andino Aug 2018 – Present · On Site (Bogotá, Colombia)

Teacher of Math and Programming related topics, focused on Linear Algebra, Programming Basics and UI Development.



Side Projects

- **The Pairs Game** | Built using React
- Next Stop | Built using React, Typescript, and Firestore